## Bruno P. Kinoshita

Barcelona – Spain (UTC+1)

I have **20 years of experience** working in different industries such as telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, civil construction, and start-ups, with a **wide variety of roles** (developer, quality engineer, devops, architect, etc.). I program in Python, Java, JavaScript, PHP, and Shell Script. I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level in Spanish and Japanese, and basic in French and Te Reo Māori.

## **Education**

○ Diploma in Business Administration, Mackenzie University 2008 – 2009

o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University 2003 – 2007

## **Experience**

O Workflow Engineer @ BSC — Barcelona Supercomputing Center

09/2022 - current

- Autosubmit Python development for HPC. Responsible for deliverables (workflows, ontologies, provenance) for European Commission funded projects such as Destination Earth Climate Digital Twins, European Digital Twin Ocean EDITO, European Open Science Cloud EOSC, and eFlows4HPC. Mentorship of new developers and students (Cantabria Uni, UPC).
- Software Engineer @ Curii (Remote NZ/EU/USA)

12/2021 - 09/2022

- CZI grant to work on the Common Workflow Language **CWL**, CWL Viewer (**Java** Spring Boot), cwltool (**Python**), documentation, and Outreachy mentorship (**Python**, **Git**, **JavaScript**).
- O Java Engineer, Research Software Engineer @ NIWA

06/2017 - 10/2021

- Java JEE development of climate products for EcoConnect web services (used by Fire Services NZ, Māori TV, and DOC-NZ). Python and JavaScript development for the Cylc workflow manager using JupyterHub, GraphQL, Vue.js, Conda, containers (Docker, Singularity), HPC (NeSI-NZ).
- Full Stack Software Developer @ Spark Ventures

10/2016 - 06/2017

- AWS development, build systems, containers, and Java development using SpringBoot.
- **DevOps** ② NIWA National Institute of Water and Atmospheric Research

04/2015 - 09/2016

- Configuration management with Puppet and Ansible, automation, Java. Jenkins Cl.
- O Big Data Engineer @ Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)

05/2014 - 03/2015

- Impala, HDFS, Hadoop. Cobol for mainframes, Java. Development company first Big Data business cases.
- O Software Engineer, Infrastructure Engineer, Software Architect @ Tokio Marine

10/2011 - 05/2014

- Java development with Servlets, Portlets, and **LifeRay** modules. SSO with **OpenAM**. **Jenkins** Cl and **Puppet**.. **ActiveMQ** cluster, internal workshops, **SSO**, new Portal with Liferay. Company-wide KPI **monitoring**.
- Senior System Analyst @ Lojas Riachuelo

07/2011 - 09/2011

- Java Swing development for retail POS system.
- O Senior Software Quality Engineer @ Vivo (Telefonica)

01/2010 - 06/2011

- CRM development with Java and GWT. CI with Hudson, Sonar, Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.
- O Senior Software Engineer @ Nossa Caixa Bank

04/2008 - 12/2009

- .NET C# and Java support. Mainframes integration with Cobol, MQSeries, DirectConnect, Uniface.
- O Value Added Services intern, Jr. System Technician, Jr. System Analyst @ Claro 07/2004 03/2008
  - **Java web development** and **J2EE** using Servlets, EJBs, JMS. **Java Swing** and J2EE development on the VAS middleware platform. Partner onboarding, marketing campaigns, billing integration.